Guide to the James Lippincott Goodwin Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Pine Acres Farm Correspondence, 1918-1965; Series IX
  - G, General, 1943-1960 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    This folder contains correspondence with purchasers of wood and produce; directions to Robert Green, foreman of the farm during the illness of Edson Stocking.
  - Garden and Grounds, 1955, 1958 (Box 32, Folder 28)
    This folder contains information on blight-resistant Chesnut trees and Narcissus bulbs for Pine Acres Farm.
  - Gillett's Fern and Flower Garden Farm, 1931, 1940 (Box 32, Folder 29)
    These flowering bush orders are for Pine Acres Farm.
  - James L. Goodwin, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 30)
    Here is a 1953 Permit to Kill Deer at Hampton and Chaplin property.
  - Gordon, Mrs. Faun J., 1962-1964 (Box 32, Folder 31)
    This folder contains correspondence between Mr. Goodwin and Mrs. Gordon, while she's in charge of office affairs at Pine Acres Farm during Edson Stocking's illness.
  - H, General, 1940-1965 (Box 32, Folder 32)
    This folder contains acknowledgement of thanks to Mr. Goodwin from the Hampton Bird Club, Hampton Congregational Church, and Hampton Fire Department; letters confirming cord-wood offers, and employees relations.
  - Hampton, 1915-1921 (Box 32, Folder 33)
    Itemized accounts of the cost of repairs on the Barn in 1915; building expenses for the bungalow in 1915; erection of a barn in 1918 and maintenance of the buildings, 1919-1921.
  - Hampton Forests, 1940-1943 (Box 32, Folder 34)
    Tabulation of Pine Plantation and Hardwoods at Hampton Forest and Chaplin Forestry; Included also a History of Pine Acres Farm to 1941.
  - Hartford Accident and Indemnity Company, Payroll (Farm), 1946-1963 (Box 32, Folder 35)
    Wage Statements and Employer's First Report on Injury for the various accidents of the employees at Pine Acres Farm.
  - I, General, 1921, 1940, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 36)
    United States Income Tax Forms.
  - Insurance, L. W. Button and Son, 1963-1964 (Box 33, Folder 37)
    Increased home coverage for the Goodwin Hampton Farm House.
  - Inventory Records, Farm, 1941-1942, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 38)
    Inventory Records; Farm, Timber and Operating Accounts; Comparative Statements of Expenses and Receipts for Pine Acres Farm.
  - Inventory Records, Farm, 1948-1957 (Box 33, Folder 38a)
    December Inventory Records of Pine Acres Farm including all items from apple equipment to pulpwood.
  - Inventory Records, 1958-1963 (Box 33, Folder 38b)
    December Inventory Records.
  - J, General, 1936-1960 (Box 33, Folder 39)
    Correspondence relating to customer puchase of farm produce, farm equipment, farm employment, and repairs to the farm buildings.
  - K, General, 1941-1965 (Box 33, Folder 40)
    Correspondence relating to farm produce purchases, farm employment; Correspondence with Professor Raymond Kienholz, Forestry Department, University of Connecticut, concerns sale of land to him and use of forestry students in surveying work.
  - L, General, 1940-1966 (Box 33, Folder 41)
    Sales of cord-wood and fence posts to individuals and towns such as Lisbon; business affairs of Little River Grange, and farm management; Employment, repairs of buildings and equipment.
  - Log and Tie Cuttings, Guarco and Halbach, 1944-1945 (Box 33, Folder 42)
    Tabulations of cord-wood cut by forestry workers, Guarco and Halbach.
  - Lumber and Wood Utilization Report, 1943 (Box 33, Folder 42a)
    941 Report on the "Current Utilization of Lumber Forest Rehabilitation".
  - M, General, 1939-1964 (Box 33, Folder 43)
    1939 Pine Acres Farm Milk Record, and correspondence with Mr. Kenneth Moore, Yale School of Forestry, regarding data on sawing and seasoning red pine lumber.
  - Markets for Wood, 1921, 1939 (Box 33, Folder 44)
    List of brick yards and wood dealers.
  - Memoranda, Current, 1949-1951 (Box 33, Folder 45)
    Directives from Mr. Goodwin to Mr. and Mrs. Stocking regarding farm and book keeping operations.
  - N, General, 1941-1963 (Box 33, Folder 46)
    General farm correspondence property, equipment repairs.
  - New England Homestead, Springfield, Massachusettes, 1921-1934 (Box 33, Folder 47)
    Correspondence relating to the placement of advertisments, purchasing of books and renewal of subscription to this New England farm weekly.
  - New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad Company, 1924, 1934, 1935, 1945 (Box 33, Folder 48)
    Purchase of the "Clancy Farm" in Hampton by James L. Goodwin from the Railroad.
  - New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad Company, 1935-1945, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 49)
    Request by Mr. Goodwin for a private railroad crossing at Hampton.
  - Northeastern Forestry Company, Cheshire, Connecticut, 1921, 1924, 1929 (Box 33, Folder 50)
    Orders of Pine transplants for Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association and Pine Acres Farm.
  - O, General, 1929-1950 (Box 33, Folder 51)
    Correspondence with general contractors, insurance concerns and lawyers collecting debts owed to Mr. Goodwin.
  - Orchards, Apple, 1930-1950 (Box 33, Folder 52)
    Correspondence with the Connecticut Polomogical Society and Massachusetts Department of Agriculture; Lease of the Pine Acres Farm Apple Orchards to Clark Stocking, and tabulations of the costs of operating the orchards, 1930-1943.
  - Orchards Leased to W. Clark Stocking, 1945-1947 (Box 33, Folder 53)
    1944 and 1946 Lease of Orchards to W. Clark Stocking, 1945-1947.
  - P, General, 1935-1961 (Box 34, Folder 54)
    Farm management; and Mr. Goodwin's 1955 Talk to the Hampton Grange on Pine Acres Farm.
  - Payroll Auditor's Reports, Compensation Information, 1940-1945 (Box 34, Folder 55)
    Annual Payrolls for Pine Acres Farm, 1940-1943; Accident and compensation reports filed with Allen, Russell and Allen Insurance agents; Statement of Audit Adjustment filed with the Hartford Accident and Indemnity Company.
  - Pine Acres Accounts, 1928-1953 (Box 34, Folder 56)
    Forestry Accounts, 1928-1940; Forestry Products 1938-1947; Also Hen Account, 1949.
  - Pine Acres Farm Analysis, Burlingame, King and Dunk, Incorporated, 1933 (Box 34, Folder 57)
    Changes in farm management to put Pine Acres Farm on a more solvent basis.
  - Pine Acres Farm History (Box 34, Folder 58)
    Original 36 page history of Pine Acres written by James L. Goodwin.
  - Pine Acres Farm History, Original Manuscript (Box 34, Folder 58a)
    Original 36 page history of Pine Acres typographical paste-up of the book to be published on the history of farm from 1914-1950.
  - Pine Acres Inventories, 1929-1956 (Box 34, Folder 59)
    Inventories of Capitalized expenses and receipts in Hampton Forest, 1929-1951; Statement of Resources and Liabilities, 1951, 1953, 1954, 1955, 1956.
  - Pine Acres Inventories, 1956-1960 (Box 34, Folder 60)
    Resources and Liabilities; Merchandise Inventory and Depreciation Tables.
  - Pine Acres Inventories, 1941-1948, 1954-1962 (Box 34, Folder 61)
    Inventories of stumpage, cord-wood, timber, property and houses; Statement of Resources and Liabilities.
  - Pine Acres Farm, Milk and Petty Cash, 1943-1944 (Box 34, Folder 62)
    Monthly milk, gas, and petty cash records for 1943 and 1944.
  - Pine Acres Farm, Milk, Gas, and Petty Cash Records, 1945 (Box 34, Folder 63)
    Monthly bills and records of petty cash, milk and gas.
  - Photographs, Negatives, Snapshots, 1915-1928 (Box 35, Folder 64)
    Photographs, negatives and snapshots mainly used in the publishing of the History of Pine Acres Farm.
  - Photographs, Negatives, Snapshots, 1935-1950 (Box 35, Folder 65)
    Many of these Pine Acres Farm negatives, snapshots and photographs were selected for use in the History of Pine Acres Farm.
  - Plantations, 1921-1960 (Box 35, Folder 66)
    Itemized record of plantations: man labor hours, procedures, work accomplished, sale, inventories of trees, expenses, purchases from Keene Forestry Associates, hurricane reports, and types of trees planted and sold.
  - Pine Acres Farm, Plantings, Annual Expenses and Receipts, 1924-1955 (Box 35, Folder 66a)
    Information and tabulations of Annual Expenses, 1924-1955; Pine Acres Farm Products obtained, 1951-1955.
  - Pine Acres Farm Plantings, and Transplants, 1950-1961 (Box 35, Folder 66b)
    Summary of Farm Plantings, 1950-1961.
  - Posts and Treating, 1949-1952 (Box 35, Folder 67)
    Correspondence with the Wood Treating Chemicals Company of St. Louis, ordering chemicals for wood treatment; 1952 Agreement between the State of Connecticut and James L. Goodwin for the purchase of posts by the State from him.
  - Property, Hampton and Chaplin, 1913-1935 (Box 35, Folder 68)
    Listing of property purchased, purchase price; former owner, date and kind of deed from 1913-1932; Abstracts to titles of Cedar Swamp lots; Correspondence with Roger Davis, Attorney, regarding his professional services in purchasing properties in Hampton and Chaplin.
  - Q, General, 1953 (Box 35, Folder 69)
    There is one letter.
  - R, General, 1924-1959 (Box 35, Folder 70)
    General Farm Correspondence includes an agreement between James L. Goodwin and the Hampton Ration Board for their use of part of the Pine Acres Farm office in 1943.
  - Rulings, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 71)
    Internal Revenue Bureau, Rulings that cutting trees and boughs by Pine Acres Farm workers is considered a forestry operation.
  - S, General, 1929-1961 (Box 36, Folder 72)
    General farm correspondence includes a legal dispute with the Schorer Company, food service equipment manufacturers; Correspondence with the Stocking family and Connecticut purchase of Highway Department treated poles.
  - Sales Tax Returns, State of Connecticut, 1947-1955 (Box 36, Folder 73)
    Work sheets and Quarterly Sales and Use Tax Returns Forms for 1947-1955.
  - Sales Taxes, State of Connecticut, Permit Numbers and Literature, 1930-1963 (Box 36, Folder 74)
    Connecticut tax forms, rules and regulations concerning the payment of the Sale Tax; Blank Certificates of Exemption for Purchase of Materials, Tools and Fuel, and Resale Certificates with Rules and Regulations persuant to this Resale.
  - Sales Tax Returns, State of Connecticut, 1956-1962 (Box 36, Folder 75)
    Work sheets and Quarterly Sales and Use Tax Returns Forms for 1956-1962.
  - Social Security and Income Taxes, Farm, 1943, 1945-1948 (Box 36, Folder 76)
    Work-sheets, correspondence and analysis such as the Quarterly Classification of Pay Roll for Income Tax Reports, January 1-March 31, 1946 and Hearing before the Unemployment Commsssion.
  - Statistics of Timber Estimates, 1928-1951 (Box 37, Folder 77)
    Work-sheets of Timber Estimates by year, board feet, cords and kind of thinning.
  - Stocking, Carolyn J., 1959 (Box 37, Folder 78)
    Correspondence concerns registration forms for Personnel and machinery registration.
  - Stocking, Edson, 1951-1961 (Box 37, Folder 79)
    Correspondence between Mr. Goodwin and his Pine Acres Farm Superintendent, Edson Stocking, contains directives and reports on farm management, personnel, Timber Estimates and work by Connwood, Incorporated.
  - Stocking, Edson, 1928, 1941, 1962-1964 (Box 37, Folder 80)
    Correspondence between Mr. Stocking and Mr. Goodwin includes lists of Timber and Cord Wood Volumes for 1928 and 1941; News of Mrs. Stocking's convalescence; 1961 Pine Acres Farm Timber Estimates figures listing compartments, Subcompartments, acreage and land classifications together with a summary sheet for the entire farm.
  - Stocking, Marion, 1951, 1955-1958, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 81)
    Communication between Marion Stocking, Daughter of Edson Stocking and Office worker, Pine Acres Farm and Mr. Goodwin or his Secretary, Miss Virginia M. Wright.
  - T, General, 1942-1954 (Box 37, Folder 82)
    General correspondence concerning payment for farm stock, purchase of furniture and information on turkeys.
  - Tax Lists, Hampton and Chaplin, 1927-1963 (Box 37, Folder 83)
    Connecticut Taxable Property List forms from 1941 to 1963 for Pine Acres Farm.
  - Timber Estimates Pine Acres Farm, 1951-1961 (Box 37, Folder 84)
    Estimates by various agencies such as Connwood, Richard Ballou and University of Connecticut Forestry students taking Timber Estimates.
  - Timber Hardwood, 1935-1938, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 85)
    Timber Purchase Agreements with the Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation for hurricane damaged logs; appraisal of damage done to the coniferous plantations of Mr. Goodwin's at Hampton by the 1938 Hurricane; Farm Inventory Accounts, 1928-1940; Forestry Accounts, 1938-1940; Timber Inventory, October-November, 1940; Timber Inventory by Compartment, 1940-1941.
  - Timber Hardwood, 1928, 1938, 1940-1941, 1943, 1946, 1948 (Box 38, Folder 86)
    Agreement between Connecticut and James L. Goodwin whereby permission is granted to the State to use CCC personnel managed by Fire Warden to clear wood of fire hazards; 1928-1940 Inventory of the timber of the entire farm and cost figures for cutting and skidding cord-wood, lumber and posts; 1938 list of logs sold to Northeastern Timber Salvage Adminstration in 1939 after Hurricane of 1938; Cost figures on sawing from 1939-1942; Statement of Net Worth of compartments, 1941-1946; 1946 Inventory of logs and cordwood; Report on Pine Acres cord plot by H. A. McKusick, Silviculturist.
  - U, General, 1923-1963 (Box 38, Folder 87)
    United States Department of Agriculture correspondence; 1936 Soil Conservation Program and Forest Service communications; University of Connecticut correspondence with Raymond Kienholz, Professor of Forestry.
  - Unemployment Compensation, 1947-1963 (Box 38, Folder 88)
    Communication with Connecticut Department of Labor regarding benefits to farm laborers; forms, Statement of Wages Paid; An Appeal by one of Mr. Goodwin's former farm employees.
  - V, General, 1933-1950 (Box 38, Folder 89)
    General farm correspondence.
  - W, General, 1948-1960 (Box 38, Folder 90)
    Contributions by Mr. Goodwin to the Storrs Church and the Windham County Hospital; billing various purchasers of posts and cord-wood.
  - Wild-Life, 1956-1957 (Box 38, Folder 91)
    Correspondence with Governor Ribbicoff, Senator Lynch and Representative Pearson urging approval of a bill giving wild life conservation officers use of a two-way radio for their automobiles.
  - Withholding Exemption Certificates, 1950-1962 (Box 38, Folder 92)
    Employees Withholding Exemption Certificates for 1950-1962 including over fifty farm employees.
  - Y, General, 1950 (Box 38, Folder 93)
    There is one letter to Young Brothers Company.
  - Z, General, 1934, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 94)
    Directives to Zlotnick's Garage, authorizing automotive repairs.
  - Zoning Board, Hampton, 1945 (Box 38, Folder 95)
    Mr. Goodwin's search for Zoning information for Hampton from towns of Windsor and Simsbury.
- Pine Acres Farm Current, 1948-1961; Series X
  - Pine Acres Farm, Clancy Farm, 1948 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    Work sheets of timber estimates, old field notes, listing of mixed hardwood and swamp hardwoods.
  - Pine Acres Farm, Conversion Table, 1951-1961 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    Conversion table giving a key to compartments, labels, area, type of stand; Local volume tables: hard and soft maples, birches, oak, tulip, poplar, white ash and hickory; Hampton, Chaplin, and Orchard Hill area compartment work sheets.
  - Pine Acres Farm: Cruise Line Map Sheets, 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Hampton Forest, April-May, 1961 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Chaplin Forest, April, 1961 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Orchard Hill, January February, 1961 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Pine Acres Farm Field Sheets, 1951-1953 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    1951 Timber Survey: Paul Koelle, Joe Sposta, Charles Hodson, John Olsen; Work sheets and Geological Survey Map, Hampton, Connecticut, 1953.
  - Pine Acres, Forest Type Acreage, 1961 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    Hampton Area in acres; Tally Scale sheets for 1960-1961 Cruise including house and grounds, plantations, mixed hardwood, swamp hardwoods, orchard and fields, pine hardwoods, open swamp, pond, hemlock hardwoods, brush, sawmill, blueberry; Stumpage cuttings of cordwood, 1951-1961; 1962 trees per acre.
  - Pine Acres, Hampton Forest, 1961 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    Work maps.
  - Pine Acres, Heights, 1951 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    Work sheets and graphs of types of wood and height in Orchard Hill, Hampton, and Chaplin Forests.
  - Pine Acres, Incidental Information, 1940-1960 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    Work sheets, total height and volume of timber, 1941, 1951, and Cuttings, 1941-1950.
  - Pine Acres, Miscellaneous Work-sheets, 1932-1951 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    1951 Timber Survey; 1932 Oregon Company Timber Survey; 1949 Work-sheets; 1954 Reuben Pearl estimates; 1951 inventory; 1941 Cord-wood, Land Improvement work-sheet; 1940 Timber Survey.
  - Pine Acres, Orchard Hill Standard Table Mixed Hardwood Type, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    Trees per acre standing, work-sheets; Volume totals, 1961; Summary of Timber Survey, 1961.
  - Pine Acres Farm Tally Sheets (Box 40, Folder 11)
    Field notes, listing sheets, estimate sheets of Chaplin and Hampton; Soft Maple, Swamp hardwoods, Hemlock, White Ash Pine, and hardwoods, found in the 1961 complete cruise.
  - Book: Pine Acres Farm, Timber Survey Notes, January, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 11a)
    Contents: Hampton Forests; Field notes; Addenda; Index to lines; Location of ends of lines; Chaplin Forest Field Notes.
- James L. Goodwin Business Ledgers and Records, 1913-1964; Series XI
  - Annual Reports
    - Pine Acres Farm Annual Reports, 1916-1946 (Box 41)
    - Pine Acres Farm Annual Reports, 1941-1961 (Box 42)
    - Pine Acres Farm Annual Reports, 1952-1964 (Box 43)
    - Pine Acres Farm Annual Reports, Duplicates (Box 44)
  - Cash Ledgers
    - Surveying Accounts, 1932-1950 (Box 45)
    - Carthage Account Ledgers, 1927-1952 (Box 45)
    - Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association Ledgers, 1933-1954 (Box 45)
    - Pine Acres Monthly Time Book, 1944-1946 (Box 45)
    - Property Ledgers: Guild House, Cannon House, Chapel House, Ford House, 1929-1946 (Box 45)
    - Pine Acres Farm Cash Ledgers (Box 46)
    - Pine Acres Farm Accounts, Receivable, 1929, 1955-1963 (Box 46)
    - Pine Acres Farm Cash Ledgers (Box 47)
    - Pine Acres Farm Bills Payable, 1930-1964 (Box 47)
    - Pine Acres Farm Cash Ledgers (Box 48)
    - Pine Acres Farm Trial Balance, 1914, 1915, 1932-1955 (Box 48)
    - Pine Acres Farm Cost Accounts: Forestry, Apple Orchards, Reforestation, 1913-1914, 1918-1927 (Box 49)
    - Pine Acres Farm Pine and Hardwood Thinning, 1914-1931 (Box 49)
    - James L. Goodwin Cash Journals, 1933, 1914-1915, 1937 (Box 50)
    - James L. Goodwin Cash Journals, 1937-1946, 1946-1954, 1955-1960, 1961-1962 (Box 51)
    - Financial records: Pine Acres Farms Total Report, 1962-1964 (Box 52)
    - Shaker Pines Forestry Corporation: (Box 52)
    - Capital and Stock subscriptions, 1937-1940 (Box 52)
    - Receipts and Expenditures, 1937-1940 (Box 52)
  - Pine Acres Farm Account
    - Pine Acres Farm Accounts, 1917-1918 (Box 53)
    - Pine Acres Farm Accounts, 1919-1924 (Box 54)
    - Pine Acres Farm Accounts, 1920 (Box 55)
    - Pine Acres Farm Accounts, 1921 (Box 56)
    - Pine Acres Farm Accounts, 1922 (Box 57)
    - Pine Acres Farm Accounts, 1923 (Box 58)
    - Membership Cards of the Talcott Mountain Forest Protection, 1923-1954 (Box 58)
    - Pine Acres Farm Accounts, 1924-1925 (Box 59)
    - Pine Acres Farm Accounts, 1926 (Box 60)
    - Pine Acres Farm Inventory, 1919-1922, 1923-1928 (Box 60)
    - Pine Acres Farm Accounts, 1927-1928 (Box 61)
    - Apple Orchards Accounts, 1919-1941 (Box 61)
    - Pine Acres Farm Accounts Ledger, 1929-1932 (Box 61a)
  - Farm Labor Accounts
    Includes the following items: man work hours, jobs performed, total daily accounts, wages, and use of time of equipment. Records date from 1927-1963 with the exception of one year missing, 1943.
    - 1927-1929 (Box 62)
    - 1930-1932 (Box 63)
    - 1933-1935 (Box 64)
    - 1936-1938 (Box 65)
    - 1939-1941 (Box 66)
    - 1942-(1943 missing) 1944 (Box 67)
    - 1945-1947 (Box 68)
    - 1948-1950 (Box 69)
    - 1951-1953 (Box 70)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 71)
    - 1957-1959 (Box 72)
    - 1950-1961 (Box 73)
    - 1962-1964 (Box 74)
    - Man Labor Records indicate the number of hours which Pine Acres Farm Laborers worked on the following operations: Timberland, Plantation weeding, House, Orchards, Machinery, Buildings, Garden, dam and lake, maple syrup and wild-life.
      - 1929-1942 (Box 75)
      - 1943-1963 (Box 76)
  - Miscellaneous Ledgers
    - Pine Acres Land Purchase, 1913-1935 (Box 77)
    - Pine Acres Forest Walk Book, "Connecticut Woodlands", 1954-1964 (Box 77)
  - Payroll Notebooks and sheets
    - Pine Acres Farm Payroll Books, 1929-1950 (Box 78)
    - Pine Acres Farm Payroll Sheets, 1954-1964 (Box 78)
    - Payroll Sheets:
      - Avon, 1933-1938 (Box 79)
      - Simsbury, 1931-1937, 1939-1940 (Box 79)
      - Hampton, 1913-1945 (Box 79)
    - Pine Acres Farm Petty Cash Records, 1958-1961 (Box 79)
    - Pine Acres Farm Gas and Oil Records, 1958-1961 (Box 79)
    - Pine Acres Farm Payroll Books, 1946-1951, 1962-1964 (Box 80)
    - Pine Acres Farm Payroll Books, 1951-1960, 1952-1954 (Box 81)
    - Pine Acres Farm Payroll Books, 1950-1964 (Box 82)
  - Payroll Notebook and sheets
    - Simsbury Time Sheets, 1945-1956 (Box 82a)
    - Simsbury Time Sheets, 1957-1965 (Box 82b)
  - Survey and Field Note Book
    - Twenty books surveying Louisiana, Connecticut, Massachusetts and North Carolina, 1908-1931. (Box 83)
    - Six books and field notes surveying Pine Acres, Simsbury and Talcott Mountain, 1928-1957. (Box 84)
  - Timber Records and Estimates
    - Pine Acres, 1926-1928 (Box 85)
    - Forest Plantations, 1915-1928 (Box 85)
    - Pine Acres, 1927-1928 (Box 86)
    - Chaplin Forest Timber Estimates (Box 86)
    - Pine Acres, 1927-1929 (Box 87)
    - Timber Cruise Note Book. (Box 87)
    - Pine Acres, 1928-1938 (Box 88)
    - Hampton, Orchard Hill, Chaplin Forest Timber Record. (Box 88)
    - Pine Acres, 1928 Timber Inventory (Box 89)
    - 1962-1972, Hampton Timber Estimate (Box 89)
    - Pine Acres, 1932-1962, Hardwood Record (Box 90)
    - 1940-1961, Timber Estimate (Box 90)
    - Pine Acres, 1940-1950 (Box 91)
    - Tract Cards, Hampton and Chaplin; Stumpage Cuttings (Box 91)
    - Pine Acres, 1941-1972 (Box 92)
    - Chaplin, Hampton, Orchard Hill Timber Records and Estimates. (Box 92)
    - Carthage, 1927-1929, Timber Cruise Note Book
      - 1930-1934, Timberland Volumes and other Growth Tables. (Box 93)
    - Carthage, 1930-1940, Timber Records and Estimates, 1962 Time Report. (Box 94)
    - "Woodford Timber Survey, 1941 Farm Tally Sheets, 1912 Timber Survey" (Box 94a)
    - "Tally Sheets, 1951 Timber Survey" (Box 94b)
  - Work Sheets
    - "Work Sheets, Forest and Farm Accounts, 1914-1950 (Box 94c)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 95)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 96)
    - 1955 (Box 96a)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 97)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 98)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 99)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 100)
    - 1964 (Box 101)
  - Timber estimates Chaplin Forest, 1927-1928 (Box 101)
  - "Miscellaneous and Duplicates, Booklets, State Park Ledger" (Box 102)
  - "Duplicates" (Box 103)
  - Documents and printed ephemera (Box 104)
    Includes notebooks pertaining to Goodwin's study of forestry; typed papers and reports; correspondence and notes concerning land held by various Connecticut towns; printed matter from the Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association (constitution, annual meeting minutes, circular letters, and leaflets); trail maps; brochures; and newspaper clippings on forest preservation.
    - Additional material (Box 105)
    - Additional material (Box 106)
- James L. Goodwin Ledgers, 1928-1965; Series XII
  - L1 Great Pond Nursery and Forestry Accounts, 1939-1941 (Box 107)